Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（赤司）言ったはずだ
I told you.
I am absolute.
絶対は僕だと
終わりだ 真太郎
It's over, Shintaro.
Akashi!
（緑間）赤司ー！
I must express my respect for all of you.
改めて敬意を表する
最後まで—
Not a single one of you lost the
will to fight until the end.
誰１人 闘志を失わなかった
だが—
But you fell short.
届かない
Sleep now, veteran kings.
眠れ 歴戦の王よ
I Can't Help But Laugh
（審判）試合終了！
The game is over!
86対70で洛山(らくざん)高校の勝ち 礼
With a score of 86 to 70, Rakuzan High wins!
Bow!
（選手たち）
ありがとうございました
Thank you!
（小堀(こぼり)）なんか—
Rakuzan is kind of quiet.
粛々としてるな 洛山は
More than happy, they seem relieved
this critical game is over.
喜ぶと言うより—
山場を１つ越えて
ホッとしてるような感じだ
（笠松(かさまつ)）当然だろう
Of course. They expect to win.
勝って当然 優勝以外はすべて失敗
Anything but victory is failure.
最強たるべき そのプレッシャーは
想像を絶する
The pressure of being the
best exceeds imagination.
絶対 負けてはならない
They must not lose.
That is the fate of an emperor.
それが帝王の宿命だ
真太郎
Shintaro...
We lost,
負けなのだよ
but next time
だが次は必ず—
we will win.
ウチが勝つ
僕からは礼を言うよ 真太郎
I should thank you, Shintaro.
久しぶりにスリルのある戦いだった
It's been a while since I last
played such a thrilling game.
だが 悪いが
その握手は受けることはできない
But unfortunately, I can't shake your hand.
勝利を欲するのなら
もっと非情になれ
If you desire victory,
you must become cold-hearted.
Victory is everything.
勝利こそが すべてだ
僕は オマエたちの
敵であることを望む
I wish to be your enemy.
そうか
I see.
変わらないな 赤司
You haven't changed since then, Akashi.
あのときから
Even so,
だが それでも—
勝つのだよ 次は
we will win next time.
Hold your heads high!
（大坪(おおつぼ)）全員 胸を張れ
Look sharp until we leave!
退場するまで
だらしない姿を見せるな
We're not the only ones who fought!
戦ったのは オレたちだけじゃない
応援席前に整列！
Line up in front of the stands!
（選手たち）
応援 ありがとうございました
Thank you for your support!
（高尾(たかお)）ベスト４かぁ
The top four, huh?
It's about what I expected.
まぁ こんなもんっしょ
よくやったよなぁ あの洛山相手に
We did pretty well against Rakuzan.
Huh? Shin-chan, are you heartbroken?
あれ？ 真(しん)ちゃん 傷心ヤバイ？
けど—
But...
ワリィ
Sorry.
I can't
今はちょっと—
console you right now.
慰めてやれねえわ
I know.
（緑間）だろうな
Me, too.
だがオレもだ
悔しいな
Losing is frustrating.
やはり
負けるというのは
Rakuzan
Shutoku
（紫原）16点差
A 16 point difference.
I guess that sounds about right.
まぁ こんなもんかな
内容的には もっと競ってても
おかしくなかったけどね
I thought the game would
actually be a little closer.
It's true that Shutoku was strong,
but an emperor is even stronger.
（氷室(ひむろ)）確かに秀徳(しゅうとく)は強かった
だが それでもやはり—
帝王の力は その上を行くか
特に…
Especially...
But why do I feel so uneasy?
だが何だ？ この違和感は
It didn't seem as though
they were holding back.
決して手を抜いているようには
見えなかったが—
それでも果たして—
Was that really Rakuzan's full strength?
あれは洛山の全力だったのか？
Was that Akashi Seijuro's full strength?
あれは
赤司征十郎の全力だったのか？
Kaijo
Seirin
（観客１）
淡々としてるな 両チームとも
Both teams look really calm.
（観客２）けど昔—
But a long time ago, apparently Seirin
beat Kaijo in a practice game.
海常(かいじょう)は誠凛(せいりん)に
練習試合だが負けてるらしいぞ
（観客１）マジかよ
Seriously?
I see.
（氷室）
なるほど 因縁の対決なんだな
It's an old rivalry.
（紫原）の割には なんか…
Yeah, but...
...it's pretty quiet for that.
静かだねぇ
ラスト！
Last!
おい 黄瀬
Hey, Kise.
Go say hello to them.
なんか 軽くあいさつしとけ
Hey!
（黄瀬）ヘイ！
（小金井(こがねい)）おう！
Is that
（伊月(いづき)）これは まさか—
a lane up?
レーンアップ？
I didn't tell you to go that hard.
軽くっつったろ
That's what you call a declaration of war.
（黄瀬）宣戦布告ってやつっス
A declaration of war?
（土田(つちだ)）宣戦布告って…
今のジャンプ力 まさか…
Was that jumping power...
Yeah.
ああ 火神(かがみ)と同じくらい跳んでた
He jumped about as high as Kagami.
Don't just stand there, idiot.
（日向(ひゅうが)）
何 ボサッとしてんだ ダアホ
お返し
Return the favor.
本家を見せつけろ
Show them the original.
（火神）ウッス
Yes, sir.
オラァ！
（観客１）やり返した
He got them back!
（観客２）
しかもレーンアップ･アリウープ
A lane up alley-oop!
（観客１）
どっちもホントに高校生かよ？
Are those guys really high school students?
Anyone can do that.
あれぐらい普通だし
負けず嫌いだね
You really hate to lose, don't you?
Captain, I've been trying to contain
myself, but I can't anymore.
（黒子(くろこ)）キャプテン
ずっと抑えてたんですけど
ダメです
I'm so excited,
（黒子）ワクワクして—
開始が待ちきれません
I can't wait for the game to start.
You idiot, so are we.
ダアホ オレらもだ
そんで それは—
So is
今ここにいる全員がだ
everyone else here.
It's starting.
（観客）始まるぞ
The miraculous rising star, Seirin High,
奇跡の新星—
誠凛高校
そして伝統のブルーを背負う
青の精鋭 海常高校
and the blue elite, Kaijo High.
Let's have a good game.
よろしくお願いします
（笠松）よろしく
Good game.
Huh?
Last time he seemed like
an inexperienced captain.
前はキャプテンとしては—
まだまだ若いって
印象だったんだけどな
さすがに ここまで
勝ち上がってきただけはある
You can tell how hard
he's fought to get here.
いいねぇ そうこなくちゃな
Good. I couldn't ask for more.
遠慮なくリベンジできるってもんだ
Now we don't have to show any
restraint when we get our revenge.
（木吉(きよし)）お…
どうした？ 伊月
少し表情 硬いぞ
What's wrong, Izuki?
Your expression's a little stiff.
Oh, I'm fine.
ああ 大丈夫
If it is, it's just because
I'm a little nervous.
だとしたら
少し緊張してるだけだよ
むしろ黒子が言ったように
ワクワクしてる
Like Kuroko said, I'm excited.
Though I'd considered our opponents
the enemy in previous games,
今までの試合は—
相手をどこか敵と思うところが
あったけど—
今 感じてるのは—
what I feel now is a pure,
unadulterated competitive drive.
裏表のない気持ちのいい闘志だけだ
I wonder what drives me to it.
とうしてかな
伊月…
Izuki...
最後のは マジで要らなかったな
You could've skipped the last part.
（日向）おい コガー
スタメンチェンジ
Hey, Koga! We're changing
our starting lineup!
What?!
（木吉）けど まぁ—
But I know what you're trying to say.
言いたいことは分かるよ
楽しんでこーぜ
Let's have some fun.
Kiyoshi Teppei...
以前の誠凛と
一番 違う点はあいつだ
He's the greatest difference
between the old and new Seirin.
気合い 入れないとな
I'd better psych myself up.
だから…
So...
Could you stop looking around
for your type of girls, Moriyama?
好みの女の子探して
キョロキョロすんのやめて 森山(もりやま)
（森山）え？
（早川(はやかわ)）頼んますよ もいやまさん
Huh?
Please, Moriyama-san!
Do you even want to win?
やう気 あうんスか？
Want to win?
（森山）やる気？
バカ言え
Don't be stupid.
Do you know how long I've
waited for this day?
この日を
どれだけ待ち望んだと思ってる
ありすぎて
さっきから女子が目に入らん
I'm so focused on this game,
I haven't noticed any girls.
参ったな
I'm at a loss.
別にいいだろ それで
There's nothing wrong with that.
Yeah, Moriyama-san!
もいやまさん よっしゃー！
オエもやいますよ！
ウチャクチャやいまっすー！
I'll do my best, too!
I'll give it everything I've got!
（黄瀬）火神っち
Kagamicchi.
That day, I experienced the frustration
of defeat for the first time.
あの日—
生まれて初めて
試合に負けた悔しさ
今日まで１日も
忘れたことねぇっスよ
I haven't forgotten it for a single day.
（黄瀬）黒子っちと連係で？
He's coordinating with Kurokocchi?
（火神）黒子！
Kuroko!
（笠松）アリウープだ！！
It's an alley-oop!
（黄瀬）させねえっスよ！！
No, you don't!
I don't need you to pay me back!
テメーのお返しは
もう いんねーよ！
Because the game ends now!
これで 終わりだからな！！
（黄瀬）けど おかげで１つ
気づいたんス
But thanks to you, I realized something.
オレ やっぱバスケが好きっスわ
I love basketball.
それこそ オレのすべてを
懸けられるぐらいに
So much that I can devote
my entire self to it.
だから—
That's why
もう絶対 負けねえ
I won't lose anymore!
Kise...
（火神）黄瀬
気づくの遅くね？
Shouldn't you have noticed sooner?
What?!
それより—
Anyway,
なんか
丸くなっちまってんじゃねえの？
you've gone kind of soft.
細けえことは もういいだろ
Don't worry about the small stuff.
こっちはウズウズして
しょうがねえんだ
I'm raring to go.
とっとと やろうぜ
Let's get this started already.
（黄瀬）
黒子っちも同意見って感じっスか？
Kurokocchi, do you feel the same way?
Yes.
はい
I'm also thinking about
あとボクが思っていることは—
how much
ボクは—
I disliked you.
黄瀬君のことが嫌いでした
ボクは黄瀬君のことが嫌いでした
What?
What?!
そこまでハッキリ言われると
さすがに…
Why do you have to be so blunt about it?
けど それはいい意味で です
But I mean it in a good way.
Huh?
I will now announce
tomorrow's starting lineup.
（赤司）明日の試合の
スターティングメンバーを発表する
４番 赤司征十郎
No. 4, Akashi Seijuro.
６番 青峰大輝
No. 6, Aomine Daiki.
No. 7, Midorima Shintaro.
７番 緑間真太郎
５番 紫原 敦
No. 5, Murasakibara Atsushi.
そして５人目は—
The fifth man is
No. 8, Kise Ryota.
８番 黄瀬涼太
All right! I'm finally
in the starting lineup!
（黄瀬）
っしゃー！ やっとスタメンっス
What do you mean, finally?
（緑間）何がやっとだ
If anything, you got in too soon.
むしろ早すぎるくらいなのだよ
（青峰）
足 引っ張んじゃねえぞ 黄瀬
Don't hold us back, Kise.
大丈夫っスよ
Don't worry.
I have Kurokocchi to thank for
his passionate training!
これも黒子っちの
熱心な教育のおかげっスね
（黒子）
ボク 別にバスケは教えてませんが
I didn't teach you to play basketball.
明日の試合は大船に乗った気持ちで
オレに任せてよ
You can rest easy and leave
tomorrow's game to me.
泥船の間違いじゃない？
Don't you mean you'll
sink us like a mud boat?
Yeah, probably.
（青峰）ああ かもな
Like the boat in "Kachi-Kachi Yama."
（緑間）かちかち山か
ちょっ！ なんで そうなるんスか？
Why would you assume that?
（黒子）
黄瀬君がバスケ部に入って—
Once you joined the basketball
team, I was assigned to train you.
すぐにボクが教育係につきました
その分 黄瀬君のことを
少し特別に感じていた
Because of it, I thought
of you in a special way.
けど—
But you surpassed me in the blink of an eye.
黄瀬君は あっという間に
ボクを抜いてしまった
才能が違うということは
分かっています
I knew our abilities were different.
それでも—
But
I was frustrated and didn't want to lose.
ボクは悔しかったし—
負けたくないと思いました
つまりボクは—
In other words, though it was
one-sided, I've always
一方的ですが
あのときからずっと—
considered you
黄瀬君のことを—
my rival.
ライバルだと思ってました
I don't know what to say.
参ったな
いい意味どころか—
You meant it in a good way?
最高に燃えるんスけど そういうの
I couldn't be more fired up!
（審判）それでは これより—
The game between Kaijo High and
Seirin High will now begin!
海常高校 対 誠凛高校の試合を
始めます
礼！
Bow!
（選手たち）
よろしくお願いします！
Let's have a good game!
（日向）伊月！
Izuki!
（リコ）今日の試合—
Today's game will be nothing like the others.
恐らく 今までと
まったく違う展開になるわ
一言で言えば—
In short, we'll have to
establish and hold a lead.
ウチが先行して逃げ切る展開よ
It's what we have to do to win.
というより 勝つためには
そうしなければいけないのよ
（リコ）
黄瀬君のパーフェクトコピー
Kise-kun's Perfect Copy is too strong.
あれは あまりに強力すぎる
ハッキリ言って
今の私たちに止めることは—
Honestly, it's practically impossible
for us to stop it right now.
ほぼ不可能と考えたほうがいい
時間制限がある以上—
Because there's a time limit on it,
使ってくるとしたら まず終盤
he'll probably use it in the
final stages of the game.
We have to create an
insurmountable lead by then.
それまでに何としても—
相手が挽回不可能な点差を
つけなければならない
In other words,
つまり—
先手必勝！
we'll strike first to win!
Attack from the start!
開始から攻めまくれ！
（早川）あ！
（笠松）バニシングドライブ？
The Vanishing Drive!
All right, Kuroko!
よっしゃー！ 黒子！
（森山）こいつ—
He's already breaking out
two of his special moves?
いきなり必殺技 ２連発かよ
The Phantom Shot!
ファントムシュート！
よし！
All right!
What?
まさか開始からいきなり？
Is he already...
One of the things Kagamicchi
said before the match
試合前に
火神っちが言ってたことで—
１つだけ
心外なことがあったんっスわ
rubbed me the wrong way.
誰がいつ丸くなったって？
Who's gone soft?
All right!
よし！
He's fast!
（木吉）
速い！ あそこから追いつくのか？
He caught up from over there?
（小堀）“後出しの権利”か
The Rite of Postponement!
ナイスパス！
Nice pass!
（黄瀬）えいっ
（日向）うわっ
黄瀬！
Kise?
（日向）クッ！
体感するとマジで実感する
I can feel it when I play against him.
今のブロックは
まさに紫原のそれだ
That was Murasakibara's block.
Kise!
（笠松）黄瀬！
クッ！ させるか！
No, you don't!
フェイク？
A fake?
（木吉）しかもこれは
青峰と同じチェンジオブペース！
And that's Aomine's change of pace!
Midorima's shooting ability
and Aomine's agility.
（伊月）緑間のシュート力に
青峰のアジリティ
ひとつひとつでも
強力すぎるくらいなのに—
They're strong enough on their own.
複合されたら
こんなのどうすれば？
What are we supposed to
do when they're combined?
上等だ 黄瀬！
Bring it on, Kise!
火神！ 頼む
Kagami, please!
（黄瀬）無駄っスよ
This is futile.
No one can stop me now!
今のオレは 誰にも止められない
まさか 今のは…
Was that...
瞬時に相手の動きのコピーを
可能にする—
His keen observation skills
that allow him to copy
an opponent's movements in a second...
精密な観察眼
今までの試合で培った経験則
The experience he's gained
from our previous games...
そしてセンス
His natural sense for the game...
Though he's not absolute,
ヤツのように絶対ではないが—
それに限りなく近い精度で—
he can see the future with
nearly perfect accuracy.
未来を見ることができる
（火神）
赤司のエンペラーアイまで…
He can even copy Akashi's Emperor Eye?
（海常部員たち）
いいぞ いいぞ黄瀬！
That's it, that's it, Kise!
クソが！
Damn it!
どの技も—
He's replicating abilities by compensating
for what he lacks with something else.
足りない要素を違う要素で補い
再現している
Strictly speaking,
they're not exactly the same.
厳密にはまったく同じではない
But,
だが—
単なるマネと呼ぶには
あまりにもレベルが高すぎる
they're more than just imitations.
パーフェクトコピー
The Perfect Copy is invincible.
まさに無敵だ
（リコ）やられた！
They got us.
Huh?
Only Kagami-kun's Zone can
withstand Kise-kun now.
今の黄瀬君に対抗できるのは
火神君のゾーンだけ
But from our previous games,
でも これまでの傾向から—
開始直後に火神君が
ゾーンに入ることは まずない
we know Kagami-kun never enters
the Zone at the start of a game.
They struck at exactly the right time.
ベストなタイミングで
仕掛けてきたわね
じゃあ—
Then will Kise stay this way
until he reaches his time limit?
これから制限時間が切れるまで
黄瀬はこのまま？
No. He won't use it all now.
いいえ ここで
使い切ることはないはず
けど たぶん
このままだと—
But if nothing changes,
this won't be all the damage we take.
ダメージは
これだけじゃ済まない
We won't let our guard down like before.
（武内(たけうち)）
以前のような油断は もうせんぞ
You are one of the strongest teams.
名将率いる最高のチーム
そのつもりで
全力で戦わせてもらおう
With that in mind,
we'll fight you with everything we have.
（日向）
光栄だけどワリィな オッサン
It's an honor, but sorry, old man.
それでも こっちのやることは
変わんねーんだよ
That doesn't change what we have to do.
Izuki!
伊月！
止められないなら
こっちも点取るしかねえだろが！
If we can't stop you,
then we just have to score!
ウチは 攻めて
ナンボだっつーんだよ！
We're an offensive team!
The Barrier Jumper!
（森山）バリヤジャンパーか
黒子！ 行けー！
Kuroko, go!
Not even Murasakibara could stop that shot.
（日向）紫原でも
止められなかったシュートだ
Stop it if you can!
止められるもんなら
止めてみやがれ！
黄瀬 対 黒子！
Kise versus Kuroko!
ファントムシュート対
パーフェクトコピー
Phantom Shot versus Perfect Copy!
Sorry, but switching to
a pass won't save you.
（黄瀬）悪いけど—
パスに切り替えたところで
無駄っスよ
Even if I can't see it, the ball's
still flying through the air.
見えなくてもボールは飛んでいる
打つ方向が分かれば…
As long as I know where it's going,
止められる
I can stop it!
Not even Murasakibara could
stop that invincible shot,
（日向）紫原でも止められなかった
無敵のシュートが…
ブロックされた
and he blocked it?
（木吉）今のは—
He
predicted its angle with the Emperor Eye
エンペラーアイで
打ち出し角度を先読みし—
紫原のブロックで軌道を封殺
and stopped its trajectory
with Murasakibara's block.
見えていないまま
力づくで止められた
He couldn't see it, but he
stopped it through brute force.
（火神）黒子 大丈夫か？
Kuroko, are you okay?
いえ—
No.
I'm beat.
参りました
やっぱり黄瀬君は すごい
Kise-kun is amazing.
完全にボクの負けです
I lost.
手ごわすぎて—
He's so strong,
I can't help but laugh.
笑っちゃいますね
Preview
（リコ）試合開始早々の
パーフェクトコピー
He started using his Perfect
Copy just as the game began.
やられたわ
He got us.
We were supposed to strike first,
but now we're on the defensive.
（降旗(ふりはた)）先攻逃げ切りどころか
逆にこっちが攻められてる
Things aren't looking good.
（リコ）
このペースのままじゃマズイわね
The True Light
よし！ 降旗君 出番よ
Okay! Furihata-kun, you're in!
Huh? What?!